# Sia Zeng

Graduate of Computer Science with 4 years experience in working across software development & 3 years experience in bioinformatics research. Passionate engineer & thriving analyst with the ability to apply algorithm development to solve real-world research problems.

Email: xyzeng25@gmail.com Phone: (226)-978-1560

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Basis Technologies Oct 2022 – Present

Software Engineer

- Built and maintain API microservices with Java Jersey framework, MySQL, MongoDB and Redis to support Demand-Side Platform for advertising inventory
- Participated in all phases of software development life cycle with analysis, design, development, testing, debugging and production

#### Ma Lab at the University of Waterloo

Research Associate

Jul 2021 - June 2022

- Built a software suite used for analyzing DIA mass spectrometric data sets with Java and HTML/CSS
- Designed a model for the retention time of protein in replicate runs

Shootz Tech (球秀) Sep 2021 – Sep 2022

Full-Stack Developer

- Improved video auto-editing (basketball game highlight) using AI technologies
- Worked with stakeholders to develop product strategies and drove the R&D team through end-toend product development, boosting yearly avenue by \$98k

## **PROJECTS**

#### MSTRACER - Peptide Detection Tool of Proteomics Data - Python, Java, ML

https://github.com/waterlooms/mstracer

- Designed a cutting-edge algorithm for peptide feature detection from DDA mass spectrometric data
- Applied ML techniques such as NN and SVR to improve the quality of results from 92% to 96.7%
- Achieved better results than the other tools such as MaxQuant & Dinosaur with an average of 2.2%
- Published in the Journal of Proteome Research <a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jproteome.0c01029">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jproteome.0c01029</a>

# ICU Discharge Assistance Web Tool - Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

- Extracted features of impact from the MIMIC-III clinical database; predicted ICU discharge time by applying ML techniques such as NN using Python; reached an accuracy of 87%
- Developed an interactive web tool for hospitals with JavaScript and HTML/CSS

## **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

M.S. in Computer Science (Bioinformatics Specialization)
B.S. in Computer Science (Bioinformatics Option)

Sep 2019 - May 2021

Sep 2015 - Apr 2019

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

Languages: Java, Python, C++, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Framework/Libraries: Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, Flask, Django, Maven

Tools: Postman, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS, Git, Docker, Nginx,

# **AWARD**

Terminal AI Competition Waterloo vs CMU, First Place Terminal AI Competition Midwest Regional, Second Place Sep 2020